Alim Satria Fi'i Wijaya Kusuma

HARDWARE ENGINEER · PCB DESIGNER

Sleman Regency, Yogyakarta, Indonesia

🗷 alimsatria45@outlook.com | 😭 justraven.github.io/gitprofile | 🖸 github.com/justraven | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/alimsatria

Personal Profile

A student at Universitas Gadjah Mada specializing in Instrumentation and Control Engineering Technology with a strong passion for Control Systems and Hardware Engineering. I am actively engage in diverse projects related to instrumentation and control systems, including coding microcontrollers, designing PCBs, and documenting projects using LaTeX and GitHub.

Education

Universitas Gadjah Mada

Yoqyakarta, Indonesia

Undergraduate degree in Instrumentation and Control Engineering Technology

2021 - Current

Universitas Gadjah Mada

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Associate degree in Instrumentation Technology

2017 - 2021

Work Experience_

PT. Integrasi Teknologi Unggas (BroilerX)

Yoqyakarta, Indonesia

Hardware Engineer

Jan 2021 - Mar 2022

- Developed an IoT devices to monitor the environment of broiler house.
- Responsible for the PCB design process, creating prototypes, communicating and collaborating on IoT integration in the device, and ensuring the device operates effectively.
- Technical Skills: PCB Design using KiCAD, Firmware programming using C++, Internet of Things
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication.

University Projects

Implementation of Flight Controller Design and PID Control on Quadrotor Attitude

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Undergraduate

Dec 2022 - Current

- Make and iterate PCB design of quadrotor flight controller to find the most compact and stable design using 8-bit microcontroller
- Tuning and refining the quadrotor attitude control using PID to make a stable attitude control and add feature to the program to log the IMU sensor and GPS data
- Technical skill: PCB design using KiCAD, Programinng in Processing 2 (Java), control system

Remake of Feedback ES151

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Undergraduate

Dec 2022

- I have undertaken the project of reviving and repairing an old Feedback ES151 system to make it suitable for learning and demonstrating PID control for velocity and position of a DC motor. Additionally, I am designing a Human-Machine Interface (HMI) using LabView, which will enable the machine to interact with and be controlled through a computer interface.
- Code the microcontroller using C++ and bridge the communication between the computer (HMI) and the machine
- Technical skill: Programming in C++, Building HMI with LabVIEW

Design and Implementation of Light Ambient Control System on Broiler Farm Using PID Controller

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Assosiate

2020

- I am working on the development of a device that aims to maintain a consistent level of light intensity within broiler chicken cages. This device utilizes a microcontroller connected to a light sensor and an LED. Additionally, I am designing a Human-Machine Interface (HMI) using LabVIEW. The device is capable of interacting with and being controlled through a web application that is accessible over the internet.
- Technical skill: PCB Design using EAGLE, Firmware programming using C++, HMI Programming using LabVIEW

Skills

Programming

Python, LabView, C, C++, Matlab.

Hardware Design

Kicad, Eagle

Soft Skills

Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation.

JULY 18, 2023

Interests_

Linux

Since 2017, I developed a deep affection for Linux, which I utilize extensively for coding and hardware design purposes. My preferred distribution is KDE Neon due to its visually appealing interface.

Technical Writing

I have documented several projects related to control systems and hardware design on my GitHub profile. One project that stands out as a personal favorite is the revival of an old PID tuning machine for the control system lab. For this project, I created the Human-Machine Interface (HMI) using LabView and wrote the main controller code in C++. I invite you to explore the project documentation by following this <u>link</u>.

LaTeX

I have a strong appreciation for using LaTeX to compose my lab reports, as it allows me to create visually appealing, stylish, and well-organized documents. I have even taken the initiative to develop a lab report template. Feel free to explore my template by visiting this <u>link</u>.

Languages_

English Professional proficiency (TOEFL ITP Score : 567/677)

IndonesianNative proficiencyJavaneseNative proficiency